{
	"name": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": "A patient who is experiencing aphasia is:\n\nA. not able to swallow without choking.\nB. usually conscious but has slurred speech.\nC. experiencing a right hemispheric stroke.\nD. unable to produce or understand speech.\nSee Stroke",
			"back": "unable to produce or understand speech."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": "The most basic functions of the body, such as breathing, blood pressure, and swallowing, are controlled by the:\n\nA. brain stem.\nB. cerebrum.\nC. cerebral cortex.\nD. cerebellum.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "brain stem."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": "Which of the following is characteristic of a focal-onset aware seizure?\n\nA. Normal level of consciousness\nB. Generalized twitching of all muscles\nC. Absence of breathing\nD. No change in vision, smell, or taste\nSee Seizures",
			"back": "Normal level of consciousness"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": "The spinal cord exits the cranium through the:\n\nA. vertebral foramen.\nB. foramen lamina.\nC. cauda equina.\nD. foramen magnum.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "foramen magnum."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": "Status epilepticus is characterized by:\n\nA. generalized seizures that last less than 5 minutes.\nB. an absence seizure that is not preceded by an aura.\nC. prolonged seizures without a return of consciousness.\nD. profound tachycardia and total muscle flaccidity.\nSee Seizures",
			"back": "prolonged seizures without a return of consciousness."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": "Febrile seizures:\n\nA. often result in permanent brain damage.\nB. occur when a child’s fever rises slowly.\nC. are also referred to as absence seizures.\nD. are usually benign but should be evaluated.\nSee Seizures",
			"back": "are usually benign but should be evaluated."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": "Components of the Cincinnati Prehospital Stroke Scale include:\n\nA. arm drift, speech, and facial droop.\nB. arm drift, memory, and grip strength.\nC. facial droop, speech, and pupil size.\nD. speech, pupil reaction, and memory.\nSee Patient Assessment",
			"back": "arm drift, speech, and facial droop."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": "When caring for a patient with documented hypoglycemia, you should be MOST alert for:\n\nA. an acute stroke.\nB. a seizure.\nC. respiratory distress.\nD. a febrile convulsion.\nSee Altered Mental Status",
			"back": "a seizure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": "The MOST significant risk factor for a hemorrhagic stroke is:\n\nA. hypertension.\nB. diabetes mellitus.\nC. severe stress.\nD. heavy exertion.\nSee Stroke",
			"back": "hypertension."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": "Which of the following MOST accurately describes the cause of an ischemic stroke?\n\nA. Rupture of a cerebral artery\nB. Blockage of a cerebral artery\nC. Narrowing of a carotid artery\nD. Acute atherosclerotic disease\nSee Pathophysiology",
			"back": "Blockage of a cerebral artery"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": "The three major parts of the brain are the:\n\nA. cerebellum, medulla, and occiput.\nB. midbrain, cerebellum, and spinal cord.\nC. cerebrum, cerebellum, and brain stem.\nD. brain stem, midbrain, and spinal cord.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "cerebrum, cerebellum, and brain stem."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": "When assessing for arm drift of a patient with a suspected stroke, you should:\n\nA. ask the patient to hold his or her arms up with the palms down.\nB. expect to see one arm slowly drift down to the patient’s side.\nC. observe movement of the arms for approximately 2 minutes.\nD. ask the patient to close his or her eyes during the assessment.\nSee Patient Assessment",
			"back": "ask the patient to close his or her eyes during the assessment."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": "Individuals with chronic alcoholism are predisposed to intracranial bleeding and hypoglycemia secondary to abnormalities in the:\n\nA. kidneys.\nB. pancreas.\nC. liver.\nD. brain.\nSee Altered Mental Status",
			"back": "liver."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": "Which of the following conditions would MOST likely affect the entire brain?\n\nA. Reduced blood supply to the left hemisphere\nB. Ruptured cerebral artery in the occipital lobe\nC. Blocked cerebral artery in the frontal lobe\nD. Respiratory failure or cardiopulmonary arrest\nSee Pathophysiology",
			"back": "Respiratory failure or cardiopulmonary arrest"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": "A patient who is possibly experiencing a stroke is NOT eligible for thrombolytic (fibrinolytic) therapy if he or she:\n\nA. has a GCS score that is less than 8.\nB. is older than 60 years of age.\nC. has bleeding within the brain.\nD. has had a prior heart attack.\nSee Emergency Medical Care",
			"back": "has bleeding within the brain."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": "Which of the following findings should concern the EMT the MOST when assessing a patient who complains of a headache?\n\nA. History of migraines\nB. Slow onset of symptoms\nC. Sinus congestion\nD. Neck stiffness or pain\nSee Headache",
			"back": "Neck stiffness or pain"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": "Muscle control and body coordination are controlled by the:\n\nA. cerebral cortex.\nB. cerebrum.\nC. cerebellum.\nD. brain stem.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "cerebellum."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": "Which of the following clinical signs is MOST suggestive of a ruptured aneurysm?\n\nA. Nasal discharge of blood\nB. Confusion and weakness\nC. Unilateral hemiparesis\nD. Sudden, severe headache\nSee Stroke",
			"back": "Sudden, severe headache"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": "A patient with an altered mental status is:\n\nA. usually able to be aroused with a painful stimulus.\nB. completely unresponsive to all forms of stimuli.\nC. not thinking clearly or is incapable of being aroused.\nD. typically alert but is confused as to preceding events.\nSee Altered Mental Status",
			"back": "not thinking clearly or is incapable of being aroused."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": "A 40-year-old patient without a history of seizures experiences a generalized (tonic-clonic) seizure. The LEAST likely cause of this seizure is:\n\nA. intracranial bleeding.\nB. epilepsy.\nC. a serious infection.\nD. a brain tumor.\nSee Patient Assessment",
			"back": "epilepsy."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-18",
		"label": "Chapter 18"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}